Alex Santonastaso

London, UK | +44 7570 280428 | alex@santonastaso.com | github.com/snts42 | santonastaso.codes

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Engineer with a background in Computer Science and Big Data Science. Experienced in building automation tools, data pipelines, and machine learning models using Python. I have a good understanding of APIs and cloud services, and I'm quick to learn new technologies on the job. I enjoy solving real world problems through efficient, maintainable code and collaborating to build great products and services.

SKILLS

Programming Languages & Tools: Python, Java, SQL, Git

Backend & Automation: Selenium, OpenPyXL, Pandas, REST APIs, Email Automation (SMTP)

Web & Frontend: React, HTML, CSS

Cloud & DevOps: GitHub Actions, Docker, AWS

Soft Skills: Problem Solving, Team Collaboration, Effective Communication, Agile, Scrum, Bilingual (English & Italian)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Intech Centre (National Careers Service Partner)

London, UK

Jun 2024 – Present

Python Automation Engineer

- Built and deployed multiple Python automation tools using Selenium and Pandas to eliminate repetitive admintasks, reducing manual workload by over 30 hours per week.
- **Developed exam results processing system** for the City & Guilds Evolve platform, improving reporting speed, accuracy, and turnaround.
- Automated exam results emails by integrating Amelia API data, improving client response time and satisfaction.
- Automated data entry, form submissions, and reporting to support data-driven decisions and audit readiness.
- Managed enquiries, bookings, and scheduling for private courses and exams, maintaining smooth service delivery.

Queen Mary University of London

London, UK

Lab Demonstrator

Sep 2023 - Apr 2024

- Offered individual support to students in writing and debugging Python code for Machine Learning projects.
- Helped students understand software engineering concepts, including data structures and algorithms.

PROJECTS

Automated Facial Emotion Recognition

- Implemented facial emotion recognition using **GoogLeNet CNN**, achieving **high accuracy** on a deployment dataset and improving the model's capabilities.
- Prepared and pre-processed a FER dataset, including face detection, face alignment, data augmentation, image duplicates removal, and trained a second model for recognising emotions in blurred images.

Ethereum Blockchain Data Analysis

- Performed analysis on the raw high volume data of Ethereum blockchain by implementing a set of **Hadoop** and **PySpark** Map/Reduce operations such as aggregation, moving window technique.
- Implemented data visualisation using **Matplotlib** and **Seaborn** to present key insights and trends.

EDUCATION

Queen Mary University of London

Master of Science in Big Data Science with Machine Learning Systems, **Distinction**

London, UK

Jan 2022 - Jan 2023

University of Westminster

London, UK Sep 2018 - Sep 2021

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, First Class Honours